when building a home gym bumper plates
are typically the way to go since they
offer more versatility than your
standard metal plate and guess what I've
got some brand new ones from livingfit
I'm going to be breaking down for y'all
today so let's get right to it
[Music]
what's up my people it's Jake back in
the barbin garage gym with another
review locked and loaded ready to go for
y'all this time around I'm going to be
breaking down living fits bumper plates
now if you don't know how this works in
this video today I'm going to tell you
everything you need to know about these
bumper plates from the price and the
features some pros and cons and of
course who should or maybe should not
add these to their home gym but let's
pump the brakes before I start doing all
of that I got to let you know I really
have no choice we've reviewed a ton of
bumper plates on barbin.com so if you
want to browse our best list go and
search barbin best bumper plates the
article is going to pull right up for
you and who knows you might be surprised
who cracks that number one spot
okay so let's talk about what I like
about these bumper plates and I think we
got to kick this off with all the
different buying options that are
available now it's worth mentioning I
don't have the 10 pound pair or the 55
pound pair with me right this second but
you can purchase five pounds up to 55
pounds which is really cool there's also
full sets ranging from 160 to 370 pounds
so with all that variety you know
there's a really solid chance you're
gonna find some that you know are going
to meet your requirements in your home
gym I also really like the pairing of
the low bounce rubber with the alloy
steel inserts so the low bounce rubber
obviously very nice for any you know
Olympic or CrossFit style lift where
you're repeatedly dropping that barbell
you definitely don't want it you know
just bouncing up and hitting your shin
or you know whatever the case is it's
going to be really nice it's also going
to protect the barbell you know with
that rubber and then also you know
living fit claims that these can
withstand up to 15 000 drops so it's
really nice they're going to last you a
long time they also don't stink and I'm
not that might sound a little bit weird
for me to say but if you don't already
know bumper plates tend to be pretty
stinky whenever you take them out of a
box so it was a pleasant surprise that
these just were ready to go as soon as I
unbox them and then lastly it's just the
Aesthetics you know I really like the
font they used and then also just like
the color coordination that way you know
in the beginning some people might not
know what each color represents but
after over time you'll see the green
you'll know it's 25 I have to think
twice about it just grab and go get
straight to your workout
now there are a few things that I want
to talk about that might be viewed as
some cons for some of y'all we got to
talk about money first surprisingly
compared to the rest of the market you
know these are pretty pricey and at the
end of the day I think they're gonna be
worth it and they seem to be you know
really high quality but at the same time
like I said it's a little bit surprising
how expensive these are now I also want
to talk about the thickness so really
with the 45s and probably even these 35s
a little bit too they're a little bit
thicker than you know a lot of other
bumper plates that I've reviewed and
that's going to be nice for you know say
a beginner you're learning to power
clean you only have a 45 pound bumper
plate on there it's gonna be nice
because you know the force from it being
dropped is going to be you know
dispersed throughout here and it's
thicker it's going to prevent you know
tackling bending whatever you want to
call it of the plate however
the thicker the plates are it's going to
mess with the whip of your barbell which
you know it's important when doing you
know Olympic lifts or anything like that
so it might just mess with you a little
bit you know until you get used to it
and then lastly I want to talk about the
materials while I don't necessarily
think these are made from recycled
rubber they don't feel like it haven't
experienced that when I'm working out
with them but you know it would be nice
for that to be listed on the website and
it's just not right now and then also
I'd like to know the durometer rating I
mean I can compare and contrast with
other bumper plates that I have in here
and maybe be able to you know figure out
a ballpark range of what that number is
but it's also not listed on the website
I just think that'd be kind of cool and
if you don't know what a durometer
rating is I should probably mention that
it's essentially you know how hard an
object is and how much bounce you can
expect to see out of it so you know just
those two things right there in my
opinion would be nice and kind of give
everybody you know a little bit more
closure I guess you could say
[Music]
thank you
okay so let's talk about some money now
with the living fit bumper plates and I
gotta highlight the individual pairs
first
so a five pound pair is going to run you
around 50 bucks a 10 pound pair is about
seventy dollars the 15s are around 80
bucks or so 25s are roughly 130. 35 is
around 190. 45s are about 230 bucks and
the 55s actually aren't on the website
right now but whatever those you know
are put on there those are going to be
around 270 so the lightest set is 160
pounds that's going to run you around
400 bucks the 260 pound set that's about
660 in the 370 pound set that's going to
be roughly 940 now no matter what you
decide to purchase these are not the
cheapest bumper plates on the market by
any means necessary so you know if you
want to find some cheaper ones you
definitely can but honestly y'all these
are pretty sweet and the quality you
know just the way they feel in my hands
kind of what have I what I have
experienced by working out with them I
think they're worth that price tag
[Music]
all right since we just got done talking
about pricing for those full sets let's
talk about what each full set entails
all right
so the 160 pound set is going to have
one pair of 45 25 and 10 pound plates
260 pound sets gonna have one pair of
the 45 35 25 15 and 10.
300 pound pair is you know one pair of
the 55 45 25 15 and 10. and guys I mean
honestly there's so many other options
right there I'm not going to bore you by
reading all of those as you can see you
know there's it's all laid out right
there in front of you so definitely
check that out there's really nice in my
opinion how there's so many different
buying options just gonna allow that
many more people to find a set to add to
their home gym
[Music]
okay so let's talk about the build now
of these bumper plates and some of the
features I mean bumper plates don't have
a whole lot of features but let's talk
about them anyways so once again you do
have alloy steel inserts and they're
wrapped in a low bounce rubber coating
right here it's gonna be really nice you
know there's not a whole lot of balance
which is going to be a good thing and
these could easily last you you know 10
years if you take care of them the right
way now aside from this you know five
pound plate right here which is
technically you know just a simple
change plate you know you just add five
pounds on these all have the same
diameter it's iwf standard diameter of
17.7 inches but as you may assume it's
never safe to assume anything but the
thickness is going to depend you know on
the actual weight of the plate so five
pound pair right here is pretty close to
the 10 pound which is going to be right
around 8 10 of an inch thick the 15s are
going to be 1.1 inches thick the 25s are
about 1.69 1.7 inches thick the 35s
around 2.3 inches thick 45s are about
2.9 inches thick and those 55 pound
plates are going to be right around 3.4
inches thick so once again these are all
color coordinated you know based on the
weight which is really nice in my
opinion it adds to the aesthetic I also
really like the lettering right here
just kind of looks pretty sweet and it's
kind of raised up a little bit too
almost like a 3d effect on it now I also
really like the collars right here it's
basically co-molded you know basically
one solid piece right here with the
actual you know face of the bumper plate
and the collar and that's really nice
it's going to add to that durability
then also the seams right here
they're there I mean they're evident if
you get up close and look at them which
I'll show you all in just a second but
it's not that bad you know it's better
than having you know a seam right down
the middle of them and they're just
almost non-existent which is also a
really nice thing it's going to add to
that overall durability
[Music]
all right so I just want to show you
guys you know everything up close with
these bumper plates and got to kick this
off with the Aesthetics honestly just
that contrast with the white lettering
on the colored you know it just looks
great honestly I like this I like this
font they use too and it kind of it
sticks up so it's kind of like a 3D
aspect which is really cool and
obviously you know you have your
labeling right here 35 25 pounds that's
nice for obvious reasons you want to
know which weight plate you're going to
grab and also you got the color
coordination right here all across the
board which is nice obviously it doesn't
change anything about the bumper plates
but you know if you're looking for
Aesthetics that's a nice touch right
there I want to talk about the collars
right here too
basically a co-molded collar which means
it's one piece I mean you can try but
you really can't even get your
fingernail up underneath there that's
really good for durability reasons and I
don't think you're gonna have to worry
about that at all let's talk about the
seams really quick and I was talking
about earlier how it's a good thing how
these bigger plates don't have a seam
that runs down the middle this is what
I'm talking about right here right so
this plate is designed like this because
you know it's five pound change plate
you know it's smaller it doesn't need to
hit the ground in general that's why the
diameter is not the same and that's why
they just you know made this seam the
way it is right now because like I said
it doesn't need that extra durability
now with these the seams are right here
essentially
and what they've done is they almost
like sanded it down I guess you could
say it's really smooth you know there's
really you know not a lot going on right
there just kind of seems like an edge
and that's really nice you know if you
had you know a seam like this middle one
right here that's when you would run
into into some you know durability
concerns because you would have to worry
about that seam kind of breaking apart
over time so honestly y'all these are
really nice like I said earlier I would
like to know just you know just to have
it official officially stamped whether
or not these were virgin rubber or
recycled Rubber and then the durometer
rating would be nice to know as well but
honestly these are top tier in my
opinion all right so just to show for
you guys you know how much bounce you
can expect to see out of these plates
went ahead and threw some on two
barbells right here I've got some from
Rogue that I'm going to compare to since
you know these are you know disclosed
with that drama ratings right around 88
so just go ahead and see what we're
working with here I'm gonna pull these
up
as you can see there's hardly any bounce
with those plates whatsoever let's so
let's see how these from living fit hold
up right here
there's a little bit more of a bounce
right there but honestly it's not too
far off in my opinion so you know I'm
not really an expert on durometer
ratings or anything like that but once
again you know these from Rogue are 88
so I think these from livingfit are you
know right around that ballpark range
which is really nice
foreign
bumper plates and guys if you're looking
for a pair of long lasting highly
durable bumper plates to add to your
home gym I think this is a really good
option it definitely should be in the
running that's because of the alloy
steel inserts and obviously you know the
low bounce rubber coating it's going to
protect the plate it's going to protect
your barbell it's going to protect
surrounding equipment the floors it's a
really nice touch plus living fit claims
that these can withstand up to 15 000
drops so I think it's pretty safe to say
these are going to last you around 10
years or so at least I also think the
overall thickness is going to be really
good for beginners specifically these
45s as you're learning you know proper
technique with power cleans and hang
cleans and stuff you know you're
dropping that barbell that extra
thickness is gonna you know prevent
those plates from bending on you over
time which is obviously a really good
thing and then also there's a ton of
buying options so honestly I think there
is a weight range out there you know
whether you want that full set or maybe
just get a bunch of individual pay
there's there's an option out there for
everybody
all right now what about those people
who might not want to purchase these
bumper plates and we got to talk about
the thickness first which is essentially
a two for one you know thing right here
so I just mentioned how that extra
thickness is going to be nice for
beginners it's still true it's going to
prevent the plates from bending you know
over time as it repeatedly dropped but
you know if you're somebody who's a
dedicated Olympic lifter or crossfitter
you might not like how it feels when
you're lifting with these because that
extra thickness could affect the whip of
the bar which is essentially the amount
of bounce that occurs you know during
the middle of your power clean or you
know any other lift that's like that so
definitely keep that in mind and also
you know this extra thickness
specifically with these 45s is really
what I'm kind of referring to here
you're not going to be able to have as
much space to load as much weight as you
possibly could compared to some other
you know thinner 45 pound bumper plates
so you definitely want to keep that in
mind as well especially if you're
lifting some you know eye-popping weight
just remember that and then lastly these
are kind of expensive not the most
expensive bumper plates on the market
but
certainly not the cheapest you know
they're they're pretty up there so if
you know you're on a tight budget you
might want to consider some other
options
foreign
that's all I got for you today on the
living fit bumper plates I personally
really enjoy these they look great they
feel great there's a ton of buying
options I mean there's just a lot going
on here with these bumper plates just
remember they're a little bit pricey
compared to you know the rest of their
competition and the thickness you know
might mess with certain people with how
their lifts feel and then you know how
much weight you can load onto your
barbell thanks for watching y'all hope
this video was really helpful that I was
able to break down every single thing
you need to know about these bumper
plates as always keep your eyes peeled
for my next video but I want you to do
one quick thing for me in the meantime
and I want you to head over to
barbin.com because we have a full
written review ready to go for y'all all
you got to do is search bar band Living
fit bumper plates review it's going to
pull right up for you and you can read
everything that I talked about here
today I'll catch y'all next time
[Music]